<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Eclipse fog05 - The End-to-End Compute, Storage and Networking Virtualisation solution.</title><link>https://fog05.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Eclipse fog05 - The End-to-End Compute, Storage and Networking Virtualisation solution.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fog05.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Eclipse fog05 - 0.2.2 Release</title><link>https://fog05.io/blog/2020-10-release-0-2-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fog05.io/blog/2020-10-release-0-2-2/</guid><description>We are glad to announce that Eclipse fog05 0.2.2.
This is release include the first implementation of fog05&amp;rsquo;s Orchestration Engine, namely FOrcE and provide integration with Kubernetes.
Release 0.2.2 includes also a new command line tool that allows interaction with FOrcE.
In details 0.2.2 includes :
Initial implentation of Fog Orchestration Engine (FOrcE) Kubernetes integration in FOrcE fosctl command line utility Bugfixes Instructions on how to install and use both fosctl and FOrcE are available here and here.</description></item><item><title>Edge Robotics with Eclipse fog05</title><link>https://fog05.io/blog/2020-07-ros2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fog05.io/blog/2020-07-ros2/</guid><description>Edge Robotics is emerging as a new trend and natural evolution of cloud robotics. Its aims is to leverage compute and storage resources are closer to the robots in order to augment their capabilities while keeping latency under control and enabling new use-cases.
Moreover it also introduces the possibility to elaborate data closer to where they are produced and gives the user control on the data shared with third parties like cloud platform.</description></item><item><title>Eclipse fog05 - 0.2 Release</title><link>https://fog05.io/blog/2020-06-release-0-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fog05.io/blog/2020-06-release-0-2/</guid><description>We are glad to announce that Eclipse fog05 got it&amp;rsquo;s 0.2.0 release.
This is the last release with an OCaml code-base and starting from the next development iteration there will be a migration to rust
Release 0.2.0 includes bugfixes but also new features and support for ROS2 Robotic Applications.
In details:
Improved OCI container support ROS2 FDUs management Isolation support for Native and ROS2 FDUs Decentralized Scheduler for FDUs New FDU API for more in-deep interaction with the FDUs Improved interoperability with ETSI OSM More information and .</description></item><item><title>Eclipse fog05 - 0.1 Release</title><link>https://fog05.io/blog/2020-04-release-0-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fog05.io/blog/2020-04-release-0-1/</guid><description>We are glad to announce that Eclipse fog05 got it&amp;rsquo;s first release.
It includes:
Decentralised design Pluggable design Runtime discovery of new nodes in the system Support for KVM Virtual Machines Support for binaries Support for LXD containers Experimental support for docker containers. Network virtualisation (virtual overlay LANs, routers and assignment of WiFi interfaces) leveraging Linux Bridge and ip2 toolchain Linux support APIs and SDK in OCaml, Python3, go. More information and .</description></item><item><title>Introducing Eclipse fog05</title><link>https://fog05.io/blog/2018-03-intro-0-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fog05.io/blog/2018-03-intro-0-1/</guid><description>Fog computing aims at providing horizontal, system-level, abstractions to distribute computing, storage, control and networking functions closer to the user along a cloud-to-thing continuum. Whilst fog computing is increasingly recognized as the key paradigm at the foundation of Consumer and Industrial Internet of Things (IoT), most of the initiatives on fog computing focus on extending cloud infrastructure.
As a consequence, these infrastructure fall short in addressing heterogeneity and resource constraints characteristics of fog computing environments.</description></item></channel></rss>